Hey everyone and welcome. Are you ready to unlock a brand new English superpower?
皆さん、こんにちは。新しい英語のスーパーパワーを手に入れる準備はできていますか？
Well today that's exactly what we're going to do.
今日はまさにそれをやります。
We're learning how to compare things and trust me it's one of the most useful skills you can
物事を比較する方法を学びます。これは非常に役立つスキルです。
have. So let's jump right in. So why do I call this a superpower?
さあ、始めましょう。なぜこれをスーパーパワーと呼ぶのか？
Because it lets you express so many more ideas. Suddenly you can talk about what's bigger,
それは、たくさんのアイデアを表現できるからです。突然、何が大きいか、
what's faster, or what's stronger. It is a total game changer for your English.
何が速いか、何が強いかを話せるようになります。英語にとって大きな変化です。
Let's get started.
さあ、始めましょう。
All right, let's kick things off with a little puzzle.
まずは小さなパズルから始めましょう。
Look at the sentence, Peter is younger than George.
「ピーターはジョージより若い」という文を見てください。
We're obviously comparing Peter and George, right?
明らかにピーターとジョージを比較していますよね？
So can you spot the secret code?
では、秘密のコードを見つけられますか？
What's the special word here that lets us do the comparing?
比較を可能にする特別な言葉は何でしょう？
I'll give you a hint. It's a word that ends in ER.
ヒントをあげます。それはERで終わる言葉です。
If you guessed younger, you are absolutely right.
「younger」と答えたなら、正解です。
And just like that, you found the main rule
これで、英語で物事を比較するための基本ルールがわかりました。
for comparing things in English. For most short describing words,
ほとんどの短い形容詞には、単にERを付け加えればいいのです。
we call those adjectives, all you have to do is add er to the end.
それだけです。簡単でしょう？では、これがどう機能するか見てみましょう。
That's it. Pretty cool, huh? Let's see how this works.
この文法には名前があります。それは比較級です。
So this grammar has a name, of course. It's called the comparative form.
これは、あるものが別のものよりも何かが多いことを言う特別な形です。
And all that means is it's the special form we use to say that one thing
常に二つのものを比較しています。これを覚えやすくするために、
is more of something than another thing. You're always, always comparing
私が好きな「魔法の公式」を作りましょう。
two things. Now to make this super easy to remember,
これは、ほとんどの比較文の基本的なレシピです。
let's build what I like to call the magic formula.
まず、比較する最初のものから始めます。これをAと呼びましょう。
This is the basic recipe for almost any comparison sentence you'll ever make.
そして、ここが魔法の部分です。Aの後に形容詞を置き、
and you add our secret code, R. So a word like tall becomes taller. Small becomes smaller.
これをBと呼びます。しかし、ここが重要です。「then」という言葉でつなげる必要があります。
See? Simple, right? Okay. To finish our magic formula, we just add the second thing,
多くの人がこの小さな言葉を忘れがちなので、必ず「then」を覚えておいてください。全体の形は、
which we'll call b. But, and this is super important, you have to connect them with the word then.
Aは形容詞ER、then Bです。例えば、象はネズミより大きいです。完璧です。
So many people forget this little word, so please always remember then. So the whole thing is,
このルールのいくつかの例を見てみましょう。longはlongerになります。smallは
a is adjective er, then b. Like, an elephant is bigger than a mouse. Perfect.
smallerになります。tallはtallerになり、youngはyoungerになります。
Let's look at a few more quick examples of this rule. Long becomes longer. Small becomes
もうすでにこのルールを理解してきていますね。
Smaller. Tall becomes taller and young becomes younger.
基本ルールを完全にマスターしましたね。
You ready to level up? Because now we're going to get into some pro tips for spelling.
心配しないでください。これから紹介するのは、英語を完璧に見せるための小さなコツです。
Don't worry, these are just a few little tricks that are going to make your English
3つのプロのヒントがあります。
look and sound absolutely perfect. We've got three pro tips coming your way.
まず、もし単語がすでにEで終わっている場合はどうしますか？
First, what do you do if a word already ends with an E?
次に、Yで終わる単語には特別なルールがあります。
Second, there's a special rule for words that end in Y.
そして最後に、重複文字のルールがあります。
And third, we have the double-letter rule.
一つずつ見ていきましょう。
Let's break them down one by one.
最初のプロのヒントは、おそらく最も簡単なものです。
Our first pro tip is probably the easiest one.
形容詞がすでにEで終わっている場合、
If an adjective already ends in the letter E,
例えばlargeやniceのように、ERを加える必要はなく、Rだけを加えます。
like large or nice, you don't need to add er, you just add the R.
つまり、largeはlargerになり、niceはnicerになります。これだけです。
So large becomes larger and nice becomes nicer. Simple as that.
次のプロのヒントは、Yで終わる単語についてです。
Okay, pro tip number two is all about words
例えば、easyやheavyのような単語です。
that end in Y, like easy or heavy.
これらの単語では、Yが少し恥ずかしがります。
For these words, the Y kind of gets a little shy.
ERを加える前に、Iに変わります。
It changes into an I before you add the ER.
だから、easyはeasierになり、heavyはheavierになります。
So easy becomes easier, heavy becomes heavier.
このルールは非常に一般的なので、覚えておくと良いでしょう。
This rule is super common, so it's a really good one to remember.
最後のプロのヒントは、bigやhotのような短い単語についてです。
And our final pro tip. This one is for short words like big or hot.
一つの母音と一つの子音で終わる単語です。
You know, the ones that end with one vowel and one consonant.
これらの単語では、最後の文字を双子にします。
For these, we give that last letter a twin.
ERを加える前に、二重にします。bigはbiggerになり、Gが二つになります。
We double it before we add er. So big becomes bigger with two Gs.
hotはhotterになり、Tが二つになります。
and hot becomes hotter with two Ts.
少し難しいですが、すぐに理解できるようになります。
It's a little tricky, but you'll get it in no time.
これで、基本ルールを学び、
So you've learned the main rule,
プロのヒントも学びました。あなたは準備ができています。
It is challenge time. I'm gonna give you a sentence with a blank
チャレンジタイムです。空欄のある文を お見せします。
and you've gotta fill it in with the right comparative form.
その空欄に正しい比較級を入れてください。
You ready? Let's do this. Okay, here's your first question.
準備はいいですか？さあ、始めましょう。 最初の質問です。
Tokyo is blank than New York. The word you need to change is large.
東京はニューヨークよりも空欄です。 変えるべき単語は「大きい」です。
So what do you do with it? Think back to those pro tips.
どうしますか？プロのヒントを思い出して。
And the answer is larger.
答えは「大きい」の比較級「larger」です。
Because large ends in that E, you just add an R. Excellent.
「large」はEで終わるので、Rを加えます。 素晴らしい。
If you got that right, you're off to an amazing start.
これが正解なら、素晴らしいスタートです。
All right, challenge number two. George got up, blank, then patty.
次のチャレンジです。ジョージは、空欄、 その後パティが起きました。
The word this time is early. Hmm, it ends in Y.
今回は「早い」です。うーん、Yで終わります。
What was that pro tip again? And the answer is earlier.
そのプロのヒントは何でしたっけ？ 答えは「earlier」です。
You change that Y to an I and then add er. Fantastic.
YをIに変えて、erを加えます。素晴らしい。
You are really getting the hang of these rules. Awesome work.
ルールをしっかり理解していますね。 素晴らしい仕事です。
Okay, last one. You can do it. The coffee was blank, then the tea.
さて、最後の問題です。あなたならできます。 コーヒーは空欄、次にお茶です。
Your word is hot. Remember that final pro tip, the double letter rule.
あなたの単語は「熱い」です。最後のプロの ヒント、二重母音のルールを思い出して。
What do you need to do here?
ここで何をする必要がありますか？
And the correct answer is hotter with two teas.
正しい答えは「hotter」、Tを二重にします。
You remember to double that last letter before adding ER? Perfect.
ERを加える前に最後の文字を二重にするのを 忘れませんでしたか？完璧です。
You completely aced the challenge. Amazing job.
チャレンジを完全にクリアしました。素晴らしい仕事です。
So let's just take a moment to realize
少し時間を取って、
how this one new skill makes your English so much stronger.
この新しいスキルがあなたの英語を どれだけ強化するかを実感しましょう。
You've learned a ton today, and this is gonna make your speaking and
今日はたくさん学びましたね。これが あなたのスピーキングと
your writing way more interesting and powerful.
ライティングをより面白く、力強くします。
So let's do a quick recap. First, remember the magic formula.
では、簡単に振り返りましょう。まず、 魔法の公式を覚えてください。
A is something er, then b. The main rule, just add er.
Aは「何かのer」、次にBです。 基本ルールは、erを加えるだけです。
Then are pro tips. If it ends in e, just add r.
次にプロのヒント。Eで終わる場合は、 Rを加えます。
If it ends in y, change it to i-e-r.
Yで終わる場合は、Iに変えてierにします。
And for those short words like big or hot, you double that last letter.
そして「big」や「hot」のような短い単語は、 最後の文字を二重にします。
That's the whole shebang. And that is it.
これが全てです。それが全てです。
Just like that, your English is already smarter
こうして、あなたの英語はすでに 数分前よりも賢く、
and stronger than it was a few minutes ago.
強くなっています。
Keep practicing, keep comparing things around you,
練習を続け、周りのものを比較し続けて、
and keep up the great work. You're doing an awesome job.
素晴らしい仕事を続けてください。 あなたは素晴らしい仕事をしています。
See you next time.
次回お会いしましょう。